Finding Aid for the Inesita Papers LSC.2365
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Correspondence, 1913-2012
  - Letters to Inesita from Maruja Martín Mayor, 1960-2009; 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 3-6)
    Letters from Inesita's friend from Madrid, Maruja Martín Mayor, describing her day-to-day, as well as information about Inesita's flamenco costume orders. Enclosures include drawings with Inesita's measurements, lists, invoices, business cards, and photographs. Postcards and greeting cards are also included. Some letters are addressed to Bob Dworkin.
  - Letters between Inesita and various people, 1968-2012 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
    Includes letters by Inesita to friends, dance organizations, universities, newspapers, and others about show bookings, past performances, and her day-to-day activities. Also includes letters from people, such as other musicians and artists, praising Inesita for performances and inquiries about dance classes.
  - Printouts of email between Inesita and various people, 2007-2011 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Includes email covering different topics, such as praises for performances and details about show bookings. Some emails are reactions to specific content and stories found on Inesita's blog or website. Also includes printouts of photograph attachments.
- Series 5: Additional materials, 1923-2018
  This series includes various manuscripts of The Mystery of Flamenco lecture-demonstrations, as well as notes and research material related to this piece, which was written by Bob Dworkin. This series also includes a significant amount of photographs of Inesita, as well as some of her own personal keepsakes, which include a press book with newspaper clippings of advertisements and reviews of early flamenco shows; passports and union cards; a Lester Horton Lifetime Achievement Award; and Inesita's first dance dress, sewn by her paternal grandmother. A manuscript of Inesita's autobiography, Inesita: A Dancer's Life is also included in both paper and digital (one CD) formats.
  This series contains audiovisual and digital materials, which includes two VHSes, one labeled as "Inesita: 45 min (enhanced) for Donald to make copies," and the other as "Reel 2 1/23/88"; one unlabeled 1/2 inch videotape; seven unlabeled 1/4 inch audiotapes; two vinyls and one CD of Inesita in Flamenco and Classic Spanish Dances; and two CDs: one of Inesita at the piano accompanying her father on the violin and one of her performing his compositions on piano.
  - Personal materials, 1925-2005 (Box 9, Folder 3, Box 10, Folder 3-4, Box 11, Folder 8, Box 16)
    Includes various items kept by Inesita over the years, such as her elementary school diploma, business cards, union cards (Actors' Equity Association, Screen Actors Guild‐American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, American Guild of Musical Artists), brochures, receipts, flyers, programs, clippings, and printouts from web searches. Inesita's first dance dress from 1925, sewn by Aurelia, her paternal grandmother is also included (box 16).
  - Photographs of Inesita, 1928-2016 (Box 13, Folder 1-3, Box 15, Folder 2-4)
    Includes primarily black and white (10 x 12 and 10.5 x 14 inches, and mounted prints of 12 x 16 inches) photographs of Inesita in various costumes typical of Spanish dances, either posing or dancing alone or with others (her husband Bob Dworkin, artists, celebrities, friends). This includes several photographs from the beginning of Inesita's career in the 1940s. There are also color photographs (3.5 x 5 inches) of her playing the harpsichord. Inesita wrote on the back of each photograph with more information about the image.
  - Press book with newspaper clippings of reviews and advertising, 1939-1954 (Box 15)
  - Music and Dance in California and the West book, 1948 (Box 10)
    Includes an article written by Inesita, "Flamenco and Castanets."
  - Audio recording of Inesita playing the piano with Willy Stahl on the violin, 1948; Stahl, Willy (Box 12, Laptop Reading Room laptop)
    Includes one CD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of audio.
  - Ballet Today and Dance Magazine clippings of reviews, 1954-1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Inesita in Flamenco and Classic Spanish Dances audio recordings, 1954, 2014 (Box 12, Box 15)
    Includes United States and United Kingdom vinyl record releases (1954), as well as the record jacket for the French release. Also includes one U.S. CD release (2014).
  - Posters advertising performances, 1955-1957, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Writings by Inesita, circa 1950s, 1988-2012 (Box 9, Folder 4, 7)
    Includes various documents written by Inesita, including a eulogy for her husband, costume lists, program notes, remarks, personal statements, a resumé of performances, and a document titled "A Laboratory Workshop for Education in the Arts and Humanities." Also includes printouts of screen captures of Inesita's text documents in process.
  - The Mystery of Flamenco scripts and research materials, 1961-2001; Dworkin, Bob (Box 2, Folder 4-6, Box 4, Folder 4)
    Includes several versions of The Mystery of Flamenco, a lecture-demonstration written by Bob Dworkin and presented by Inesita throughout her performing life. This also includes their research notes, articles, and other research material.
  - Audio recording of Inesita performing Willy Stahl's compositions on piano, 1994 December 31; Stahl, Willy (Box 12, Laptop Reading Room laptop)
  - Photograph album of Inesita at her home and studio, 2000; Shapiro, Katie (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Includes both black and white and color prints of Inesita posing in her flamenco costume.
  - Video of Inesita in her studio dancing, 2003 (Box 12, Laptop Reading Room laptop)
    Includes one DVD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of video.
  - Inesita: A Dancer's Life manuscript, circa 2005 (Box 10, Folder 1-2, Laptop Reading Room laptop)
    Includes both digital and hard copies of Inesita's autobiography, Inesita: Dancer's Life. The latter contains rough drafts with editors' marks. Chapters of this book are blog posts on Inesita's website, https://flamenco-inesita.com/ (last accessed July 26, 2019). Includes one CD with .001 GB (1 digital file) of text (.pdf).
  - Lester Horton Lifetime Achievement Award, 2010 (Box 14)
    Includes a glass trophy and a program with the names of all honorees.
  - Unlabeled audio recordings, undated (Box 12)
    Includes seven unlabeled 1/4 inch audiotapes.
  - Two video recordings, undated (Box 12)
    Includes two VHSes, one labeled as "Inesita: 45 min (enhanced) for Donald to make copies," and the other as "Reel 2 1/23/88." Also includes one unlabeled 1/2 inch videotape.